M Z

MORTEZA ZAKER

CONTACT

Q Location: Toronto, ON Email: smzaker@gmail.comPhone: 438-337-6600

EDUCATION

PH.D. - COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING Sep 2017

Amirkabir University, Tehran, Iran

MPHIL - COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING Sep 2015 Amirkbair University, Tehran, Iran

MASTER OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY May 2010 Multimedia University, Malaysia

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE COMPUTER SOFTWARE
ENGINEERING Sep 2004, Isfahan
University, Isfahan, Iran

SKILLS

- Oracle (11,12c):
 - Data Modeling.
 - In-memory Technology.
 - BI and Data Migration
 (Warehouse Builder/Federated
 Warehouse/ETL
 /ELT/Architecture).

AI-Knowledge Representation (Research):

- Ontology (SPARQL, RDFS, OWL).
- Knowledge Modelling and Analyzing, Portage.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly educated computer programming professional with 20+ years of experience in the field and in academia. Knowledgeable in the use of software programming applications such as Oracle and Python, and possesses experience IT systems set-up and support. Currently looking for a position as a computer programmer or IT support specialist, preferably in a managerial role.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSISTANT May 2010 - Current

University of Malaya

- Provided leadership in the IT Department, collaborating with other faculty members effectively to conduct research and produce reports.
- Delivered a critical core banking database system for Pasargad Bank as an assistant software architect to Mr. Oveysi.
- Played a major role in the designing & implementing Oracle VLDBs.

CONSULTANT Nov 2015 - Dec 2018

MAGFA Co, Iran

- Proved RFPs and served as the project manager for the implementation of a new data management software.
- Trained 10+ engineers for their roles and was a project manager for the implementation of an SMS software system.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Sep 2013 - Sep 2018

University of AmirKabir, Iran

- Served as a research assistant to Professor Mohamad Bagher Menhaj in the field of Data Representation & Presentation.
- Collected, extracted, and entered data with high degree of accuracy, and produced reports to communicate research progress & conclusions.

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR Sep 2013 - Sep 2018

Tehran South Azad University, Iran

- Taught undergrad courses in computer science while studying for one's PhD.
- Developed lectures based on books, personal research, & course objectives.

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR Sep 2012 - Sep 2018

University of Azad Tabriz, Iran

- Taught advanced database creation & maintenance to aspiring software engineers, as well as data mining and programming through Python.
- Supported grad students in selecting research topics & planning projects.

• Software:

- Software Analyzing (OO, UML, functional/non-functional requirements, SDLC).
- Programming with Embarcadero - Delphi.
- · SQL programming.

• Visualization:

- QlikView.
- Oracle.

• Networking:

- Novel Network, Cisco, Routing, Switching.
- Windows Server, Unix.
- Datacenter Concepts (Hardware/Software).

LANGUAGE

- English (Level 7)
- Farsi (fluent)
- Turkish (fluent)
- Azeri (fluent)
- **Arabic** (basic proficiency)

HONOURS

- **Doctoral Fellowship** *Azad University Tabriz* - *Sep* 2013.
- Ranked 3rd National Exam, Iran Judiciary Auditor in IT - Apr 2008.
- Ranked 1st National Employment Intake Exam (Out of 3500 Computer Engineers) - May 2000.
- Ranked 4th National Entrance Exam of Azad University (Out of 100,000 students) – Sep 1995.

BI DATA ANALYST Oct 2016 - Sep 2017

Bonyad Mostazafan, Iran

- Completed data migration and BI projects.
- Provided accurate, reliable and scalable data corresponding to source legacy system(s).
- Gathered all data into one system and central EDW.
- Holding owns approx. 1000+ manufactures and holdings.

SOFTWARE PROJECT MANAGER Feb 2014 - Sep 2016

Telecommunication Company of Iran, Iran

- Analyzed and recognized patterns from VLDB.
- Oversaw 10 developers, working under my supervision as they programmed with JAVA based on my sudo codes and commands.

NETWORK ENGINEER May 2000 - Dec 2006

Soroosh Publishing, Iran

- Setup LAN/WAN, point-to-point connections, and configured three switch layers and Wan DVB.
- Installed satellite dishes in order to line up with TV satellites.
- Maintained and monitored the connections of the ISPs.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Nov 2003 - Jun 2006

Independent Contractor

- Coded programs in diverse programming languages based on specific functionality requirements.
- Maintained detailed documentation of software development processes.
- Integrated design feedback to build & maintain user-centered software applications.

DESKTOP SUPPORT SPECIALIST Oct 1998 - May 2000

University of Motahari (IT Department), Iran

- Guide users through remote support procedures following exact scripts and processes to eliminate common causes of technical issues.
- Created technical documentation and manuals for future technical support use to keep team consistent and efficient.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

DELIVERY DRIVER Feb 2021 - Current Skip the Dishes, Vancouver, BC

TRUCK DRIVER Mar 2020 - Nov 2020 Zit Transport, Vancouver, BC

DRIVER Jan 2020 - Mar 2020 Uber, Vancouver, BC